JENEVE PILCHER

https://jcpilche.github.io | jcpilche@iu.edu | (317) 650-1460 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/jenevepilcher/

SUMMARY

Dedicated, passionate leader of computer scientists, B.S. Informatics graduate of Indiana University within three years who loves approaching a wide array of new, difficult ideas with research, being a method of positive direction for society, and learning for fun

EDUCATION

Indiana University – Bloomington, IN

Bachelor of Science in Informatics, Cognate: Business

Grace Hopper Scholar

January 2021 – May 2024

ACTIVITIES

UROC, Undergraduate Thesis - Bloomington, IN

Undergraduate Researcher

August 2022 - May 2024

- Finalized a thesis, 'Can We Use Language Models to Study Humans? Quantifying the Similarity Between Politically Opinionated LLMs and Humans' that aims to uncover whether scientists can accurately use LLMs in agent-based modeling
- Simulated beliefs and personas within language models through fine-tuning and prompt-engineering meticulously
- Learned essential thought processes of a scientist and methodological strategies to add to the public's knowledge

Computer Science Club - Bloomington, IN

President

January 2023 – May 2024

January 2022 – January 2023

Outreach Director

- Devised the three largest and most connected events IU Luddy had ever had, the first annual programming competitions
- Gained irreplaceable experience and drive for programming, leading, and innovating that influenced a deep love of science
- Selflessly leveraged business knowledge to introduce new workflow, branding, and motivation that optimizes balance, connectedness, and productivity within the computer science community, becoming a visionary of students' success

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages, Web, Libraries, AI Python, SQL, Java, Perl, HTML, CSS, LLM, Pandas, Matplotlib, Unity, C (beginner)
- OS and Applications Linux/Unix, Bash, PowerShell, MacOS, Microsoft 365, Git, GitHub, APIs, VM, Tableau, GDrive

EXPERIENCE

Observatory on Social Media - Bloomington, IN

Research Assistant

May 2024 – Present

- Informing the direction of LLM integration in agent-based-simulations with consideration for bias and alignment issues
- Searching for safe, reliable usage of LLM personas to study human interaction, opinion dynamics, and information spread
- Uncovering misinformation within the scientific community and working towards meticulous and thorough breakthroughs

Vibe Yoga Studio - Bloomington, IN

Database Design Intern, Front Desk Attendant

July 2023 - February 2024

• Taught the company how to optimize online attention through knowledge of Internet algorithms while gaining teaching expertise, academic guidance, strengthened community, and supplementation to academic success through an inspiring hobby

Hotplate - San Francisco, CA

AI & Business Development Intern

May 2023 - August 2023

• Trained an ML model to identify potential clients on social media; exercised small world theorem to personally source clients

Center of Excellence for Women and Technology - Bloomington, IN

Entrepreneurs and Tech Intern

July 2022 – May 2023

Built and taught curriculum to encourage the pursuance of entrepreneurship and technology with an empowering community